[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a188", "question": "In the cartoon \"Wacky Races\", who drove the Bulletproof Bomb?", "answer": "The Ant Hill Mob", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9c4", "question": "What commonly used drug is also used as a natural pesticide?", "answer": "Caffeine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc8feec223966ae8f8894", "question": "What lifted Frank Darabont's spirit whenever he experienced writer's block while writing \"The Shawshank Redemption\" script?", "answer": "Listening to Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart's \"The Marriage of Figaro\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c790877e98cb977789d1", "question": "Where will you find \"The Great White Way\"?", "answer": "Broadway, New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8d6", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the river Rhine?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa551cc73aa70ea0b70b21", "question": "Which district in central Tokyo is particularly famous for its electronics?", "answer": "Akihabara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7e6", "question": "What are the two main ingredients of mayonnaise?", "answer": "Oil and egg yolk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ba", "question": "Who in the world of music and born 1984 has the real name\u00a0Victoria Christina Hesketh?", "answer": "Little Boots", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae2", "question": "What 2002 movie has spawned sequels with the subtitles \"Apocalypse\", \"Extinction\", and \"Afterlife\"?", "answer": "Resident Evil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a003", "question": "What British TV series featured David Brent and Gareth Keenan?", "answer": "The Office", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ae4", "question": "Which artist is famous for his statue The Thinker?", "answer": "Auguste Rodin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ee", "question": "What two pieces are moved in chess's castling maneuver?", "answer": "The king and rook", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a51a90aac110e4167071", "question": "What is Homer Simpson\u2019s beer of choice?", "answer": "Duff", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c733", "question": "What seven-letter \"B\"\u00adword is often applied to those suffering from manic depression?", "answer": "Bipolar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd9693a23c87fd04dd15e08", "question": "The first Nobel Prize was awarded in which country?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af04", "question": "What country did the U.S. declare war against in 1846?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6017402944491cbd7c5a17bb", "question": "Who ruled Soviet Russia from 1917 to 1922?", "answer": "Vladimir Lenin -- this was the period between the Russian Revolution and the formation of the Soviet Union (U.S.S.R.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb23", "question": "What NFL team did the Denver Broncos defeat to win their second Super Bowl?", "answer": "Atlanta Falcons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afba", "question": "Who was the last Viceroy to India?", "answer": "Lord Mountbatten", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c827", "question": "The Egyptian plover is a bird best known for its symbiotic relationship with what host animal?", "answer": "The crocodile", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c231", "question": "What animal is on the cover of the Beach Boys' album \"Pet Sounds\"?", "answer": "Goat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffcfd3f9dc5ec6cd98a8322", "question": "What is the title of Leonardo da Vinci's portrait of Christ?", "answer": "\"Salvator Mundi\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133941c", "question": "What was the name of Marky Mark's backing band?", "answer": "The Funky Bunch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb4f47e83c707845b211d", "question": "What is the name of the chemical compound that makes peppers hot?", "answer": "Capsaicin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e96", "question": "What Tennessee Williams title character is married to Brick Pollitt?", "answer": "Maggie the Cat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58b8d6f32b42d4a3561a9f09", "question": "What country is Dinish Island a part of?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb0f", "question": "In what country is Guinness Stout brewed?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b65", "question": "What Kubrick film feature gangs of punks loose in future England?", "answer": "A Clockwork Orange", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc25664865c716bd8505f26", "question": "While traveling on the original \"Oregon Trail\",' what were the five infectious diseases that killed many of the travelers?", "answer": "Cholera, Dysentery, Typhoid fever, Diphtheria, and Measles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afa7", "question": "What year was the state of Israel declared?", "answer": "1948", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e98", "question": "What movie did the villain Mrs. Danvers appear in?", "answer": "Rebecca", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f837cee580c7f8fd1e60", "question": "What is the tallest mountain in the contiguous US?", "answer": "Mount Whitney", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600242794be4723ccac22186", "question": "Atticus Finch is the name of the narrator\u2019s father in which classic 1960 novel?", "answer": "\"To Kill a Mockingbird\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600241144be4723ccac2216f", "question": "Which classic artist was a preacher before he was a painter?", "answer": "Vincent Van Gogh -- He spent nearly a decade of his life in different fields, including as an language teacher and lay preacher.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339633", "question": "What Sergio Leone spaghetti western is a remake of Kurosawa's \"Yojimbo\"?", "answer": "A Fistful of Dollars", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ff", "question": "What three races must be won to capture the \"Triple Crown\" in horse racing?", "answer": "Kentucky Derby, Preakness Stakes, Belmont Stakes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc7", "question": "What is the capital of South Africa?", "answer": "Pretoria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e2", "question": "Which US state is closest to Cuba?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab3b", "question": "Which African nation gained its independence on July 9, 2011?", "answer": "South Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e1d6fe83fe1f2a824b99", "question": "What was the \"The Blitz\"?", "answer": "A term used for Germany\u2019s bombing campaign on London", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339299", "question": "What is the main difference between the character Starbuck in the 70's version of \"Battlestar Galact", "answer": "Starbuck is a female in the reboot and a male in the 70's version", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e3e", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"The River Bank\"?", "answer": "The Wind in the Willows", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600243224be4723ccac22191", "question": "Charles Marlow is the narrator of which Joseph Conrad novella?", "answer": "\"Heart of Darkness\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339148", "question": "What year marked the first appearance of Pinocchio?", "answer": "1883", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c8", "question": "What year did Pinocchio first appear in published media?", "answer": "1883", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b85", "question": "What is the name of the rabbit in the movie \"Bambi\"?", "answer": "Thumper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adfa", "question": "What serial killer struck in London in 1888?", "answer": "Jack the Ripper", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909cd88bb53d1af658864e9", "question": "What spiced wine is traditionally consumed during the winter months, and especially around Christmas?", "answer": "Mulled wine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bfdfecdb668d7dfe168b5b1", "question": "On whose 1989 \"Trash\" release were Steven Tyler and Jon Bon Jovi guest performers?", "answer": "Alice Cooper's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6ab4420565ad31a57c827", "question": "Who said, \"If it were necessary either to do wrong or to suffer it, I should choose to suffer rather than do it\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4a8", "question": "What is the official language of Liechtenstein?", "answer": "German", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133914f", "question": "Who was the Greek god of volcanoes?", "answer": "Hephaestus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390d7", "question": "Humbert Humbert is a character in which popular novel?", "answer": "Lolita", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afbf", "question": "Who was the first British monarch to live in Buckingham Palace?", "answer": "Queen Victoria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae54", "question": "Who were the architects of the Parthenon?", "answer": "Iktinos and Kallikrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c052", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Greece?", "answer": "Little owl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60078250bd51d85e222ab656", "question": "What did Claude Monet's father want him to be?", "answer": "Grocer (Monet's father disapproved of his painting. He wanted him to go into the family\u00a0grocery business.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd668e7a5bfecdd737e0874", "question": "Why is \"pound\" abbreviated as \"lb\"?", "answer": "\"Libra\" is Latin for pound or weight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d0872596a59cbdfbd37d", "question": "Who said, \" I was really too honest a man to be a politician and live\u201d?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c949", "question": "In which continent did Turkeys originate?", "answer": "North America", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ec26378dc25ca9e12ef648", "question": "Which country has been donating London's Trafalgar's Square's Christmas tree since 1947?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b298", "question": "Who was the oldest signer of the US Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b951", "question": "What board game, set during World War II, is dubbed \"A Game of High Adventure\"?", "answer": "Axis & Allies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a99b", "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano \"Popocatepetl\"?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f5", "question": "What TV mother has presided over the longest-running American sitcom ever?", "answer": "Marge Simpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a6fb90aac110e4167082", "question": "How many milliliters is a teaspoon?", "answer": "5 mL", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60077fb4bd51d85e222ab63f", "question": "What painter was summoned to Rome in 1481 to decorate the walls of the Sistine Chapel?", "answer": "Sandro Botticelli was summoned to Rome in 1481 by Pope Sixtus IV, and charged with decorating the walls of the Sistine Chapel.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ecae2b3790ded87bb38fd89", "question": "Who allegedly committed suicide in the Metropolitan Correctional Center, New York on August 10th 2019?", "answer": "Jeffrey Epstein", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6fa", "question": "What winter Olympic event combines cross-country skiing with rifle shooting?", "answer": "Biathlon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d7", "question": "What is the most common atom in the universe?", "answer": "Hydrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133928d", "question": "What title was the movie \"Evil Dead III\" released under?", "answer": "Army of Darkness", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff2146c31a458464a93c456", "question": "When was the last time Easter Sunday and April Fool's Day occurred on the same day in the 20th century?", "answer": "1956", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad9daf9e748bb36357acdd6", "question": "What is the name of the bony covering over the gills of ray-finned fishes?", "answer": "Operculum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2df", "question": "What year was actor Arthur Stanley Jefferson born?", "answer": "1890", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c9f7f3b4e2c7fbd389674e", "question": "What year was Strongbow cider introduced to the market?", "answer": "1962", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339296", "question": "What is the most common swear word used in the TV series \"Battlestar Galactica\"?", "answer": "Frak", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae5", "question": "Who played Ike Turner in the 1993 Tina Turner biopic \"What's Love Got To Do With It?\"", "answer": "Laurence Fishburne", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff20e6631a458464a93c421", "question": "First published in 1842, \"The Masque of the Red Death\" is a short story by which American writer?", "answer": "Edgar Allan Poe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe77619eec85e375820b316", "question": "What waterway divides Turkey between Europe and Asia?", "answer": "Bosporus Strait", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8bf", "question": "What is the more common name for Axilla?", "answer": "Armpit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea36a2ff048f679a45ab10", "question": "What animal is sometimes used by museums to clean skeletons for display?", "answer": "Beetles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339070", "question": "Which baseball player did a female Stephen King character loved?", "answer": "Tom Gordon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b32f", "question": "What English city was known to the Romans as Venta Bulgarum?", "answer": "Winchester", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9088901dd7bf43be5e885", "question": "What color is on the outside arc of a rainbow?", "answer": "Red", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399d3", "question": "What classic sitcom character\u2019s maiden name was McGillicuddy?", "answer": "Lucy (Ricardo)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbf996ce05a3942286f01", "question": "Who recorded the album \"Abraxas\"?", "answer": "Santana", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede5086ce05a3942286de5", "question": "Who played Karen Hill in the movie \"Goodfellas\"?", "answer": "Lorraine Brocco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de0", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"safari\"?", "answer": "Arabic", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cac8", "question": "What chemical element's atomic number is 50?", "answer": "Tin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e47", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"There's Something About Mary\"?", "answer": "Brett Favre", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa4189c73aa70ea0b70b10", "question": "Which sport is strangely associated with Christmas in Venezuela?", "answer": "Many Venezuelans traditionally roller-skate during Christmas.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c576877e98cb977789af", "question": "What is the least populous country in Africa?", "answer": "Seychelles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b13b", "question": "What frontiersman led the party that cut the Wilderness Road through the Cumberland Gap?", "answer": "Daniel Boone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e803a9de59ea584496fe9e", "question": "What was another name for Dodie Smith's \"The Hundred and One Dalmatians\" novel?", "answer": "The Great Dog Robbery", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6010c7130775fa611bce67d5", "question": "What does the Latin phrase \"Sic semper tyrannis\" mean?", "answer": "\"Thus always to tyrants\" -- It is short for \"Sic semper tyrannis ad mortem\", which means \"Thus always I bring death to tyrants\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c26c", "question": "How many wings does a flea have?", "answer": "Zero", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58c9f7b1b4e2c7fbd389674b", "question": "How is a Long black coffee different from an Americano?", "answer": "The espresso is poured on top of the hot water, instead of before", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b7ff9513a3a814d89068c53", "question": "What is Ethiopia's official language?", "answer": "Amharic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a32f", "question": "What was the debut album of the band \"Belle and Sebastian\"?", "answer": "Tigermilk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d02", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Mini-Me?", "answer": "Dr. Evil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bfdff2db668d7dfe168b5b5", "question": "Which duo is credited with inventing the \"Spinning Frame\"?", "answer": "Richard Arkwright and John Kay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7700beec85e375820b2f3", "question": "What is the smallest national park in Canada?", "answer": "Georgian Bay Islands National Park, Ontario", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff3c29e4f032c0db195b483", "question": "Who served as chief minister to King Henry VIII of England from 1532 to 1540?", "answer": "Thomas Cromwell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338adb", "question": "The comic strip \"Spy vs Spy\" debuted in which year?", "answer": "1961", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd04", "question": "In British English, what is the two-initial term for a resume?", "answer": "CV", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339052", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Cry, the Beloved Country\"?", "answer": "Alan Paton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b40", "question": "Which items are melting in Salvador Dali's painting \"The Persistence of Memory\"?", "answer": "Watches", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c70b", "question": "How many calories must you burn to lose one pound?", "answer": "3500", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c573", "question": "What kind of tree produces prunes?", "answer": "A plum tree", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339949", "question": "What character ran the general store on both \"Green Acres\" and \"Petticoat Junction\"?", "answer": "Sam Drucker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4edc106d333868d34d770", "question": "What do you call the moveable indicator on a Ouija board which is shaped like a heart?", "answer": "Planchette", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dc4", "question": "What double-word song title was a hit single by Neil Diamond?", "answer": "Cherry, Cherry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ad", "question": "Who recorded the international hit single \"Poker Face\" in 2008?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cd61bb53d1af658864e8", "question": "How old was Kevin in the 1990 film \"Home Alone\"?", "answer": "8 years old", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339504", "question": "George Costanza was a longtime employee of what sports franchise on Seinfeld?", "answer": "New York Yankees", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c567", "question": "What name is given to the device which consists of a frame with parallel wires carrying beads used for computation?", "answer": "Abacus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb53", "question": "How deep is each end zone on a CFL football field?", "answer": "20 yards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c484", "question": "What is the technical name for the shape the stackable Pringles chips have?", "answer": "Hyperbolic Paraboloid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bba8", "question": "What is the name of the Princess Mario & Luigi have to rescue in the Super Mario Brothers Nintendo games?", "answer": "Princess Toadstool/Peach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b14", "question": "What color is the little engine in the children's book \"The Little Engine That Could\"?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af62", "question": "What was Typhoid Mary's job?", "answer": "Cook", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ae9319574a5ce6b56b8235", "question": "Who was the Greek goddess of youth?", "answer": "Hebe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee8", "question": "Which battle saw the final defeat of the Jacobites in 1746?", "answer": "Battle of Culloden", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a9", "question": "Who voices the character of scientist and inventor Professor John I.Q. Nerdelbaum Frink Jr. on \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Hank Azaria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f0cfff048f679a45aaa7", "question": "Tonitrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Thunder", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e93a918d6f11f394a3b2d5b", "question": "In the manga series \"Bleach\", what is the name of Renji Abarai's zanpakuto?", "answer": "Zabimaru", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "592201b0a4edfd43a087addb", "question": "What is the first name of the fictional character \"Miss Marple\"?", "answer": "Jane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a105", "question": "Who directed the 1985 film \"Out of Africa\"?", "answer": "Sydney Pollack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e3", "question": "Who is the author of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" novel series?", "answer": "Robert Ludlum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a37", "question": "Which French term literally means \"Fat Tuesday\"?", "answer": "Mardi Gras", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c34a", "question": "What mathematical symbol could you place between 4 and 7 to get a number larger than 4 and smaller than 7?", "answer": "Decimal point", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c938", "question": "The koala eats the leaves from this tree?", "answer": "Eucalyptus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febb9c67e83c707845b213f", "question": "What do you call someone who studies sea shells?", "answer": "Conchologist", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec7", "question": "Who was fired from the Interior Department in 1865 for having written \"Leaves of Grass\"?", "answer": "Walt Whitman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c13", "question": "Who is the duo what created the TV show \"South Park\"?", "answer": "Trey Parker and Matt Stone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2dc", "question": "Avian flu in China led to 2006 price hikes in what piece of sporting equipment?", "answer": "Badminton birdies", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b04e", "question": "Which U.S. President signed the National Aeronautics and Space Act establishing NASA?", "answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a3f", "question": "What was the last name of Bill Murray\u2019s character\u2019s platoon Sergeant in the movie \"Stripes\"?", "answer": "Hulka", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb085fbcf631c2414a13b50", "question": "Who sings the \"Friends\" theme song?", "answer": "The Rembrandts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abb1", "question": "What is the nickname for Alaska?", "answer": "The Last Frontier", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5cb70c36f96e155acab35d2a", "question": "How much did the United States pay Russia per acre for the purchase of Alaska in 1867?", "answer": "About 2 Cents per acre", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be70", "question": "What is Michigan Stadium also known as?", "answer": "The Big House", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c662", "question": "What is the longest and heaviest bone in the human body?", "answer": "Femur", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c28d", "question": "What is the fruit of the \"Ananas comosus\"?", "answer": "A pineapple", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58c8a63b90aac110e416707c", "question": "What fruit oil is added to tea to create Earl Grey tea?", "answer": "Bergamot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393b6", "question": "Who does Jabba intend to feed to Sarlacc in the movie \"Star Wars - Return of the Jedi\"?", "answer": "Luke and Han", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a2c", "question": "Jenny McCarthy and Carmen Electra were both hosts on what MTV game show during the 1990's?", "answer": "Singled Out", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76643eec85e375820b27d", "question": "In which mountain range is the highest continuous paved road in the U.S.?", "answer": "Rocky Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7bfe0877e98cb9777896b", "question": "What country borders the Caspian Sea, Persian Gulf, and Gulf of Oman?", "answer": "Iran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe0e28efcbed638185eaa1e", "question": "\"Chili crab\" is a dish from which country?", "answer": "Singapore", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58dba40a874c93a3298b2142", "question": "Puccini's \"Tosca\" is based on which 1887 Victorien Sardou play?", "answer": "La Tosca", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad9de5ee748bb36357acde5", "question": "Who played Matlock in the muder mystery series of the same name?", "answer": "Andy Griffith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6002405e4be4723ccac22164", "question": "Jack Ryan is the name of the CIA analyst in author Tom Clancy's novels.  What is Jack's birth name?", "answer": "John Patrick Ryan, Sr.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febb6327e83c707845b2124", "question": "Which land mammal has the most teeth?", "answer": "Giant armadillo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a825", "question": "What large island lies about 300 miles due east of Mozambique?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071d5e3745b36be73039d7", "question": "What operation brought over 1,500 German scientists, engineers and technicians following the end of World War II to the US to aid in military research?", "answer": "Operation Paperclip", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a3", "question": "Who plays Pacey Witter on the TV show \"Dawson's Creek\"?", "answer": "Joshua Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8ad8c01dd7bf43be5e77a", "question": "Where does the color sepia come from?", "answer": "The ink of cuttlefish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf0b", "question": "How many tiles does a player play to score a bingo in Scrabble?", "answer": "7", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ae9299574a5ce6b56b822f", "question": "Who wrote \"The Rose Tattoo\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b292", "question": "What piece of technology did IBM develop in 1973 that they nicknamed Winchester?", "answer": "A disk drive", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339acd", "question": "What famous entertainer's tombstone reads, \"Everybody Loves Somebody Sometime\"?", "answer": "Dean Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cb5", "question": "What was the better-known name of Margareta Zelle, exotic dancer?", "answer": "Mata Hari", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338945", "question": "Which great painter's nickname translated literally to \"The Greek\"?", "answer": "El Greco", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c57a", "question": "What are the four layers of the rainforest?", "answer": "Emergent, Canopy, Understory, Forest Floor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea3d54ff048f679a45ab4a", "question": "What is Gregor Mendel known to be the father of?", "answer": "Genetics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f9", "question": "Which MLB player lead the American league in home runs in 2010 and 2011", "answer": "Jose Bautista", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a02d", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", Stewie took captive the cast of which hit TV show?", "answer": "Star Trek: The Next Generation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922c", "question": "What New York City night spot was the subject of a 1984 Richard Gere movie?", "answer": "The Cotton Club", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ab", "question": "What nation was led by Pompey the Great?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398b4", "question": "What character is best known for their phrase \"What's up, Doc\"?", "answer": "Bugs Bunny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae15", "question": "What English legal document was signed in 1215?", "answer": "Magna Carta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d5b", "question": "The shoe-obsessed Spats Colombo is the villain of what 1959 comedy?", "answer": "Some Like It Hot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6aa0b20565ad31a57c80f", "question": "Who was the American Ambassador to the United Nations during the Cuba missle crisis?", "answer": "Adlai Stevenson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a854", "question": "Machu Picchu is also known as what?", "answer": "Lost City of the Incas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594d06ad1a1c922dd1ac64ae", "question": "What's the official state sport of Alaska?", "answer": "Dog mushing", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a876", "question": "In what city would you find \"Peachtree Street\"?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918b", "question": "Who was the first actress to appear on a postage stamp?", "answer": "Grace Kelly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe937eb6bd93ce3a4e5f67b", "question": "Heliophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "The Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf2b", "question": "What is sometimes known as Goober Grease?", "answer": "Peanut Butter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ca", "question": "What year did Jean Anouilh write the play \"The Lark\"?", "answer": "1952", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ab", "question": "What bone, to which your ribs are attached, gets its name from the Greek for breastbone?", "answer": "Sternum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ac", "question": "What two states border Lake Champlain?", "answer": "New York and Vermont", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c847fbde8045e48466d5", "question": "What kind of unique fur does a platypus have?", "answer": "As if it weren't an odd enough creature, the platypus' fur is bioluminescent, meaning they can glow in the dark.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7bff6877e98cb9777896c", "question": "What is the earliest known walled city?", "answer": "Jericho", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c2", "question": "Which Amendment to the US Constitution gave women the right to vote?", "answer": "19th", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4d9ae308b8581f80b092c0", "question": "While filming a segment for the show \"The Grand Tour\", what car did Richard Hammond crash in June, 2017?", "answer": "Rimac Concept One", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb2d", "question": "Someone who raises false alarms is said to cry what?", "answer": "Wolf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa5b", "question": "Port Vila is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Vanuatu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ae863cc7f28483af1e7fdcc", "question": "How many territories does India have?", "answer": "7", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b52f", "question": "What plant is rum made from?", "answer": "Sugar cane", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2cd", "question": "Who played the Bishop in the 1947 film \"The Bishop's Wife\"?", "answer": "David Niven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6de", "question": "Liberty Island is located in the harbor of what US city?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c09c", "question": "What wine barrel contains 126 gallons?", "answer": "Pipe or butt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d50", "question": "What oddly worded catchphrase earned Whitney Houston a \"Big Quote\" nomination from VH-1 in 2005?", "answer": "Hell to the no!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d9", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Trans-Europe Express\"?", "answer": "Kraftwerk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339765", "question": "How does Kyra Collins die in the Sixth Sense?", "answer": "She is poisoned", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b358", "question": "What was the real name of the Boston Strangler?", "answer": "Albert DeSalvo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b697", "question": "What is a \"major-domo\"?", "answer": "A chief steward", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d119214fea7fe947a2228b", "question": "Which song from The Beatles' the \"White Album\" was originally entitled \"Maharishi\"?", "answer": "Sexy Sadie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59d185823b17032616b590ff", "question": "When was Nescafe's instant coffee first launched?", "answer": "1938", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59636c6c967692ea851899ab", "question": "What popular destination helped popularize hot dogs in the US in the 19th century?", "answer": "Coney Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d38", "question": "Who's responsible for \"The Ballad of Cable Hogue\"?", "answer": "Sam Peckinpah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b28501dd7bf43be5e79f", "question": "What does your moon sign represent?", "answer": "Your subconscious and emotions", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e5", "question": "What is known as a \"Magnum Opus\"?", "answer": "The greatest, most popular or most renowned achievement of a writer, artist or composer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe52fb81bf59ab7d2e38117", "question": "Where is Bank of America headquartered?", "answer": "Charlotte, North Carolina", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133becb", "question": "What city is the birthplace of boxer Manny Pacquiao?", "answer": "General Santos", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a90", "question": "Dr. Brown's puppy in \"Back to the Future Part II\" was named after what astronomer?", "answer": "Copernicus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb06", "question": "Since 1949, what magazine has handed out the most prestigious \"Car of the Year\" Award?", "answer": "Motor Trend", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2de", "question": "What was the better known name of outlaw Harry Longabaugh?", "answer": "The Sundance Kid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59071b743745b36be73039c1", "question": "What year did the Chew comics series debut?", "answer": "2009", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad1e", "question": "To what religious order did Mother Teresa belong?", "answer": "Little Sisters of the Poor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a39", "question": "What poet penned \"Ash Wednesday\" in 1930?", "answer": "T.S. Eliot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe904a001dd7bf43be5e876", "question": "Who did chess whiz Bobby Fischer famously defeat in 1972?", "answer": "Boris Spassky", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fedd8cb6ce05a3942286d74", "question": "Which NBA player has had a tattoo of the late Malcolm X on his left calf at least since 2012?", "answer": "Derrick Rose", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399d2", "question": "Which ghost did Carol Kane portray in the 1988 film \"Scrooged\"?", "answer": "Ghost of Christmas Present", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be81", "question": "Who was given a gift of a hat pin and a copy of \"Leaves of Grass\" on February 28, 1997?", "answer": "Monica Lewinsky", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a29a", "question": "Who directed the 1996 film \"Escape from L.A.\"?", "answer": "John Carpenter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6bc0cfb6c85e9e634ff5b", "question": "On maps, what is the technical name for the \"you are here\" arrow?", "answer": "Ideo locator", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa5", "question": "Minsk is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Belarus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b631", "question": "In NATO's phonetic alphabet, what is the letter \"A\" referred to as?", "answer": "Alpha", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea33e8ff048f679a45aaf2", "question": "Why is most pollen yellow?", "answer": "To attract bees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e19a06d333868d34d728", "question": "How long was Francisco Franco in power in Spain?", "answer": "36 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f6", "question": "What is a peanut if it is not a pea or a nut?", "answer": "Legume", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97f", "question": "What is the official residence of the president of France?", "answer": "Elysee Palace", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f8", "question": "Which actress played Forrest Gump's mom?", "answer": "Sally Field", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a59a", "question": "What ocean contains the spot where 0\u00b0 longitude meets 0\u00b0 latitude?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59008b35cf842fa4c4ba9696", "question": "What composer wrote the \"Pomp and Circumstance\" marches?", "answer": "Edward Elgar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c8a", "question": "\"Dead Men Don't Wear Plaid\" was the last film of what legendary costume designer?", "answer": "Edith Head", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9d7", "question": "Which is the most Northerly African country through which the Greenwich meridian passes?", "answer": "Algeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9bb03364247bf200fb89e", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Trafalgar\"?", "answer": "The Bee Gees", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c9", "question": "What year marked the first appearance of Pinocchio?", "answer": "1883", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fde4d76c6c6b019850c9a80", "question": "In the \"Book of Malachi\", God says that he has left the kingdom of Esau to which animals?", "answer": "Jackals", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c458", "question": "What vitamin was isolated from fish liver oil in 1917?", "answer": "Vitamin D", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae08", "question": "Which New England state was an independent republic for 14 years before joining the union?", "answer": "Vermont", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c90b", "question": "Which is the only body cell with no nucleus?", "answer": "Red blood cell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c840", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the islets of Langerhans?", "answer": "The pancreas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ce", "question": "In the Southern Hemisphere, summer begins in what month?", "answer": "December", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a4", "question": "What city is the TV show \"Sex and the City\" based in?", "answer": "New York", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ac", "question": "What is Homer Simpson's middle initial?", "answer": "J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b176", "question": "In what year did the State of California officially join the United States as its 31st state?", "answer": "1850", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a117", "question": "In the world of music how is Raymond Burns more commonly known?", "answer": "Captain Sensible", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d70", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"A Space Odyssey\"?", "answer": "2001", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb7", "question": "Which building material gets its name from Arabic for \"brick\"?", "answer": "Adobe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4c8e49076251badbead7", "question": "What was the name of the space capsule that carried the first woman in space?", "answer": "Vostok 6 -- It carried Soviet cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova in space on 1963.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59008fa6cf842fa4c4ba96bf", "question": "In what Australian state would you find the city of Launceston?", "answer": "Tasmania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d04", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Paul Shaffer?", "answer": "David Letterman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb1", "question": "What are the seven deadly sins?", "answer": "Greed, Envy, Gluttony, Sloth, Lust, Pride And Wrath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015ea40fe83fe1f2a824bef", "question": "In 2007, purported remains of what saint were found to be from an Egyptian mummy instead?", "answer": "Joan of Arc", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7bf", "question": "How many chambers does the human heart have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5937ea5908d98002fdd633a1", "question": "What is the largest body of fresh water in the world by surface area?", "answer": "Lake Superior", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392af", "question": "What pop star's fans are known as \"Claymates\"?", "answer": "Clay Aiken's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ae", "question": "What is the name of Johnny Depp's character in \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339224", "question": "Who celebrated is 111th birthday during \"The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring?\"", "answer": "Bilbo Baggins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eac", "question": "What short story begins \"$1.87. That was all. And sixty cents of it was in pennies\"?", "answer": "The Gift of the Magi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe523531bf59ab7d2e380ef", "question": "Swarovski is associated with what product?", "answer": "Chrystal jewelry", "category": "general"}]